♪Don't feel sad for the fallen flowers♪
♪ لا تشعر بالحزن على الزهور الحزينة ♪
♪Falling in the mortal world♪
♪ يتظاهر في العالم الفاني ♪
♪Keep all the memories♪
♪ استمر في جميع الذكريات ♪
♪Can't find any peace anymore♪
♪ لا يمكن العثور على أي سلام بعد الآن ♪
♪The storms can't kill my passion♪
♪ العواصف لا يمكن أن تقتل حمايتي ♪
♪But I need to endure♪
♪ لكنني بحاجة إلى تحمل ♪
♪Be serious even though I'm naive♪
♪ كن جادا على الرغم من أنني ساذجة ♪
♪If this is the destined fate♪
♪ إذا كان هذا هو القدر المقدر ♪
♪Even if I'll be hurt♪
حتى ولو تأذيت ♪
♪I'll protect the people♪
♪ سأحمي الناس ♪
♪The mountains sun and moon can be my witnesses♪
♪ الجبال الشمس والقمر يمكن أن يكون شاهداي ♪
♪Full of passion♪
♪ مليء بالحماقة ♪
♪Deep love and hatred♪
♪ الحب والكراهية العميق ♪
♪Melts in my heart along with the snow♪
♪ يذوب في قلبي مع الثلج ♪
=Royal Rumours=
= الشائعات الملكية =
=Episode 7=
= الحلقة 7 =
You two should be quiet.
يجب أن تكونا هادئين
His Highness is still sleeping.
سموه لا يزال نائمة
Your Highness.
سموك
Do you want to drink some Ginseng soup?
هل تريد شرب بعض حساء جينسنغ؟
(How much liquor did I drink last night?)
(كم من المشروبات الكحولية) هل شربت الليلة الماضية؟
She actually said that
قالت في الحقيقة
my eldest brother is better than me.
أخي الأكبر أفضل مني
I even gave her back the evidence.
حتى أنني أعيدها الأدلة
I was sincere.
كنت صادقًا
Drink!
اشربي!
"Let go of your reservations
"التخلي عن تحفظاتك
to achieve the desired result."
لتحقيق النتيجة المنشودة "
No.
لا
Qi and Ba.
تشي وأبا
- Yes.
- نعم
Get ready.
استعد
I want to go to Hua family.
أريد أن أذهب إلى عائلة هوا
Yes.
نعم
(Hua Mansion)
(طائفة هوا)
Greetings, Your Highness.
تحياتي يا صاحب السمو
Miss said
الآنسة قالت
she needs to avoid gossips,
عليها أن تتفادى الغوغاء
so she can't
لذلك لا يمكنها
accompany Your Highness today
أن ترافق سموك اليوم
for a walk.
لمرافقة
I'm not here to look for her.
أنا لست هنا للبحث عنها
I'm just passing by.
أنا مارًّا من هنا فحسب
Go to the court.
اذهب إلى المحكمة
- Yes.
- نعم
It's frightening.
هذا مخيف
Miss, don't ask me
يا آنسة، لا تطلبي مني
to pass messages like this anymore.
لإرسال رسائل كهذه بعد الآن
Protector General Hua has sent someone
المحمي الجنرال هوا أرسل شخصا ما
to send Jinpo's General A'Wa
لإرسال جنرال هوا
to the capital.
إلى العاصمة
The State of Jin and Jinpo
مقاطعة جين وجينبو
are about to discuss about the peace negotiation.
على وشك مناقشة عن مفاوضات السلام
His Majesty wants to take this opportunity
ويود جلالة الإمبراطور أن يغتنم هذه الفرصة
to hold the States Assembly
لعقد جمعية الولايات
and invite the states around
ودعوة الولايات
to send their ambassadors here.
لإرسال سفيريهم إلى هنا
My beloved ministers,
وزرائي الأحباء
what are your opinions?
ما هي آراؤك؟
Your Majesty are thinking far.
جلالتك تفكرين بعيدا
This matter brings glory to the state.
هذه المسألة تأتي بالمجد إلى الولاية
Everyone in the state should celebrate it.
كل شخص في الولاية يجب أن يحتفلوا به
I'm planning to choose
أنوي اختيار
a Ceremonial Officer
ضابط مراسم
to talk to Jinpo
للحديث مع جينبو
regarding the peace negotiation
فيما يتعلق بمفاوضات السلام
and to handle the matter of the assembly of the states.
وتناول المسألة عن جمعية المقاطعات
I didn't expect to
لم أكن أتوقع
see such a scene
رؤية مثل هذا المشهد
in my lifetime.
في حياتي
This is the demeanour of a great power.
هذا هو سلوك قوة كبيرة
Grand Preceptor, please take care.
أيها المعلم الكبير، اعتني بنفسك
I think
أعتقد
we should give the chance
يجب أن نقدم الفرصة
to the young people for such an auspicious event
للشباب لمثل هذا الحدث الميمونة
to train them
لتدريب لديهم
so that they can
حتى يمكنهم
carry the State of Jin's future.
تحمل مستقبل دولة جين
Grand Preceptor, you're right.
أيها الأستاذ الكبير، أنت على حق
Do you have a good candidate?
هل لديك مرشح جيد؟
Father,
أبي
as the eldest son,
كابن الأكبر
I should be the role model.
يجب أن أكون نموذج الدور
I'm willing to take the responsibility.
أنا مستعد لتحمل المسؤولية
I also think that
أعتقد أيضا أنه
no other candidate is
لا يوجد مرشح آخر
better than Yuanhao,
أفضل من يوانهاو
but
ولكن
I think
أعتقد
the States Assembly is a big event
أن جمعية المقاطعات حدث كبير
so we need to be more careful.
لذلك علينا أن نكون أكثر حذرا
The States Assembly is a big event.
جمعية الولايات حدث كبير
I need to think about it.
أحتاج إلى التفكير في الأمر
At the same time, I need to take
في الوقت نفسه، أحتاج إلى أخذ آراء العوام
the commoners' opinions into account.
آراء عامة الناس في الاعتبار
I'm planning to get the suitable candidate
أنوي الحصول على المرشح المناسب
through a competition.
من خلال مسابقة
Anyone who is interested
أي شخص مهتم
can join.
يمكن الانضمام
No.
لا
No way.
لا يمكن
I mustn't let Prince Ying
يجب ألا أدع الأمير ينغ
to host the peace negotiation.
لاستضافة مفاوضات السلام
Miss,
الآنسة
Prince Ying might be slow to react,
قد يكون الأمير ينغ بطيئا في الرد
but he's kind.
لكنه لطيف
At least he's not as bad as
على الأقل ليس سيئا
Crown Prince.
ولي عهد
Listen to yourself.
استمع إلى نفسك
Don't just grill the meat on one side.
لا تشوي اللحم من جانب فحسب
Don't judge the book by its cover.
لا تحكما على الكتاب من عنوانه
Do you know
هل تعرف
what he said in
ما قال في
the Hall of Great Awakening?
قاعة الصحوة الكبرى؟
The source of all problems
مصدر جميع المشاكل
is Hua family.
هي عائلة هوا
Hua family is raising an army at the border,
عائلة هوا تقوم بتشكيل جيش على الحدود
harming the people and using their money.
إيذاء الناس واستخدام أموالهم
Why not we dismiss the army
لماذا لا نطرد الجيش
and return peace to the world?
وإعادة السلام إلى العالم؟
It will express Jin's sincerity
سوف يعبر عن صدق جين
in the peace negotiation.
في مفاوضات السلام
If the army is going to be dismissed,
إذا كان الجيش سيُطرد
maybe one day
ربما يوم من الأيام
Jinpo will return.
سيعود جينبو
Prince Ying
الأمير ينغ
is either stupid or bad.
إما غبي أو سيء
Looking at the situation,
بالنظر إلى هذا الوضع
he'll surely win the competition.
من المؤكد أنه سيفوز بالمسابقة
It's a competition,
إنها مسابقة
but actually
لكن في الحقيقة
there's no other candidate.
لا يوجد مرشح آخر
Furthermore, he's a Prince.
علاوة على ذلك، إنه أمير
He stands a great chance to win.
لديه فرصة كبيرة للفوز
For now,
في الوقت الحالي
we need to find someone
نحن بحاجة إلى العثور على شخص ما
who is of equal status as Prince Ying.
من هو المتساوي في المركز مثل الأمير ينغ
Are you talking about
هل تتحدث
Crown Prince?
ولي عهد؟
But you already asked me to
لكنك طلبت مني بالفعل أن
say those things to His Highness this morning.
قولي هذه الأشياء لسمو صاحب السمو هذا الصباح
I shouldn't have done that
ما كان يجب أن أفعل ذلك
if I knew this would happen.
إذا كنت أعلم أن هذا سيحدث
That's your initial intention.
هذه هي نيتك الأولى
Let's go.
لنذهب
Where are we going?
إلى أين نحن ذاهبون؟
We'll look for His Highness.
نبحث عن سموه
We were so arrogant
كنا متعجرف جدا
like we don't want to talk to him anymore.
كما لا نريد التحدث معه بعد الآن
How are we going to convince him?
كيف سنقنعه؟
I
أنا
will talk heart-to-heart to him.
سأتحدث من القلب معه
Miss!
الآنسة!
There can't be only one
لا يمكن أن يكون هناك فقط واحد
assassin group
قاتل
from Jinpo alone.
من جينبو وحدها
Why is no one taking any action?
لماذا لا يقوم أحد بأي إجراء؟
Your Highness,
صاحبة السمو
Princess Hua is here to seek audience.
الأميرة هوا هنا لالتماس الجمهور
So fast?
بهذه السرعة؟
I'm not meeting her.
أنا لا ألتقي بها
(Righteous Radiance)
(الإشعاع المؤاتي)
Where is Princess Hua?
أين الأميرة هوا؟
She was here just now.
كانت هنا للتو
I said I'm not meeting her
قلت إنني لا أقابلها
and she didn't even have the patience to wait for me.
ولم يكن لديها لديها الصبر لانتظاري
She's lack of patience.
إنها تفتقر إلى الصبر
Your Highness.
سموك
What could she ever achieve?
ما الذي يمكنها تحقيقه في أي وقت؟
I dare not fool Your Highness around.
لا أجرؤ على خداع سموك
Fafa ran out just now.
نفذت القوات المسلحة اﻷنغولية للتو
I was just looking for it.
كنت أبحث عنها فحسب
It's my fault.
إنه خطأي
I shouldn't have let Your Highness worry.
لا ينبغي أن أذهب تقلق سموك
Princess Hua, weren't you so sure
الأميرة هوا، ألم تكن متأكدة من ذلك
of keeping a distance with me?
من الحفاظ على مسافة معي؟
Why did you suddenly look for me,
لماذا بحثت عني فجأة
a wild beast?
وحش برية؟
How would Your Highness be a wild beast?
كيف ستكون وحش برية لسموك؟
I was dizzy
كنت أشعر بالدوار
being blown by the wind
أن يتم نفخ الريح
so I was confused
لذلك كنت مشوشة
and I said the wrong thing.
وقلت الشيء الخطأ
I've come here today
لقد جئت إلى هنا اليوم
to say sorry
للقول آسف
to Your Highness.
إلى سموك
Also,
وأيضا
the distance that I talked about
المسافة التي تحدثت عنها
is the intimate distance.
هي المسافة الحميمة
Princess Hua, you're good at talking.
الأميرة هوا، أنت بارعة في التحدث
Princess,
الأميرة
how are you going to apologise?
كيف ستعتذرين؟
Your Highness, why not
صاحبة السمو، لم لا
we go out today?
أن نخرج اليوم؟
(Fragrance bathroom)
(حمامات العطور)
Exclusive bathroom.
الحمام الحصري
(Why did I agree to come here)
(لماذا وافقت على المجيء إلى هنا)
(with her?)
(معها؟)
What's wrong?
ما هو الخطأ؟
Your Highness, you don't like this place?
صاحب السمو ألا يعجبك هذا المكان؟
I'm not that casual.
أنا لست عارضة إلى تلك الدرجة
It's not casual.
إنه ليس عارض
Being with Your Highness
البقاء مع سموك
is not casual.
ليس مؤقتا
Princess...
الأميرة...
Li.
لي
Coming!
قادم!
Bring him there.
أحضره إلى هناك
Your Highness, please.
صاحب السمو، من فضلك
Your Highness,
صاحبة السمو
I asked someone to
طلبت من شخص ما
prepare that for you!
بإعداد ذلك لك!
Enjoy!
استمتعوا!
(Enjoy?)
(استمتعوا؟)
(This is punishment.)
(هذا عقاب)
This is the premium enjoyment
هذا هو التمتع بالقسط
in Qinghan Prefecture.
في مقاطعة تشينغهان
I'm sure His Highness seldom gets
أنا متأكد من أن الأمير نادرا ما يحصل على
to enjoy it in the capital.
للاستمتاع به في العاصمة
Besides it's expensive,
إلى جانب أنها باهظة الثمن
it's all good.
كل شيء جيد
I'm working so hard.
أنا أعمل بجد
I'm sure His Highness can feel
أنا متأكد من أنه يمكن لسموه أن يشعر
my painstaking effort
جهدي المضني
and put his guard down
و وضع حذره
to be my friend.
ليكون صديقي
Your Highness,
صاحبة السمو
how did it go?
كيف تسير الأمور؟
Was it comfortable?
هل كان مريحة؟
Hua
هوا
Liu
ليو
Li.
لي
You're good at taking revenge for personal grudges.
أنت بارع في الانتقام للحشود الشخصية
I'll remember what you did.
سأتذكر ما قمت به
(What's going on?)
(ماذا يجري؟)
(Was our service bad?)
(هل كانت خدماتنا سيئة)
(It's obviously comfortable.)
(من الواضح أنه مريح)
Taking a bath is comfortable.
تناول حمام مريح
Why didn't His Highness
لماذا لم يكن سموه
appreciate it?
أي تقدير؟
Do we really need to do this?
هل نحن بحاجة حقا إلى فعل هذا؟
Miss,
الآنسة
can we think of
هل يمكننا التفكير في
a reliable way?
طريقة موثوق بها؟
Either we give up
إما أن نتخلى
or we stop
أو نتوقف
looking for His Highness.
نبحث عن سموه
No way.
لا يمكن
I can never give up.
لا يمكنني الاستسلام أبدا
(Jinling Garden) Mr. Xia, you're here.
(حديقة جين لينغ) السيد شيا، أنت هنا
Please come in.
يرجى الدخول
I heard that His Majesty
سمعت أن جلالة الملك
will choose the Ceremonial Officer
سوف يختار مسؤول الاحتفال
among the younger ones
من بين الصغار
to host the States Assembly.
لاستضافة جمعية الدول
Is your father
هل والدك
supporting Prince Ying?
لدعم الأمير ينغ؟
My father is on the same side with
والدي على نفس الجانب
Minister Tian and the rest.
الوزير تيان والبقي
But, His Highness did
ولكن، صاحب السمو فعل
something really weird
شيء غريب حقا
lately.
مؤخرا
Do you know about that?
هل تعرفين عن ذلك؟
What's it?
ما الأمر؟
His Highness
سموه
is raising a musician.
يقوم بتربية موسيقي
He's composed
مؤلف
a song to praise His Majesty.
أغنية للإشادة بجلالة الإمبراطور
After His Majesty listened to it,
بعد أن استمع جلالة الإمبراطور إليها
reward was given
أعطي مكافأة
but His Highness was told
لكن قيل لسموه
not to play it
عدم اللعب
during the States Assembly.
خلال جمعية المقاطعات
Otherwise, it's going to
خلاف ذلك، فإن ذلك سوف
bring shame to the State of Jin.
يجلب العار إلى دولة جين
Your Highness.
صاحبة السمو
Princess Jiamin.
الأميرة جيامين
Miss Yao is here too.
الآنسة ياو هنا أيضا
What a coincidence.
يا لها من مصادفة
I...
أنا
What are you doing?
ماذا تفعلين؟
Why are you taking all the initiative?
لماذا تأخذ كل المبادرة؟
I...
أنا...
I'm afraid that he'd find fault with Yun Han.
أخشى أن يجد خطأ مع يون هان
We can stop His Highness
يمكننا وقف سموه
and Yun Han will change the way
و يون هان سوف يغيران الطريق
he sees us.
إنه يرانا
You're thinking so much more
أنت تفكرين أكثر بكثير
than me.
أكثر مني
Your Highness,
سموك
what are you doing here?
ماذا تفعل هنا؟
I'm competing for the role
أنا أتنافس على الدور
of Ceremonial Officer.
دور موظف الحفل
I heard that the best musician
سمعت أن أفضل موسيقي
in the capital is in this music workshop.
في العاصمة هو في ورشة الموسيقى هذه
That's why I'm here to inspect.
لهذا السبب أنا هنا للتفتيش
Wenyin and I
أنا و ون ين
are familiar with this music workshop.
على دراية بحلقة العمل الموسيقية هذه
Let me take Your Highness around.
اسمح لي أن آخذ سموك
That'd be great.
سيكون هذا رائعا
It seems like after that day,
يبدو كما لو بعد ذلك اليوم
Princess Jiamin's taste
ذوق الأميرة جيامين
has improved.
تحسنت
Please.
يرجى
Thank you, Princess Jiamin.
شكرا لك يا أميرة جيامين
(Ankang Garden)
(حديقة آنكانغ)
Not bad, Your Highness.
لست سيئة يا صاحب السمو
Your skill has improved
لقد تحسنت مهارتك
compared to a few days back.
بالمقارنة مع بضعة أيام الماضية
I feel weird too.
أشعر بالغريب أيضًا
I wonder why I'm feeling good
أتساءل لماذا أشعر بالراحة
these few days.
في هذه الأيام القليلة
Could it be that
هل يمكن أن يكون ذلك
Your Highness had a breakthrough
كان لسموك إنجاز
in talking to Princess Hua?
في التحدث إلى الأميرة هوا؟
Don't mention. She's terrible.
لا عليك، إنها مؤسفة
Let me tell you.
دعني أقول لك
She build a fragrance bathroom
تبني حمام العطر
in her mansion
في قسمها
in the western suburb.
في الضاحية الغربية
She even invited me there.
حتى أنها دعوته إلى هناك
That's too much!
هذا أكثر من اللازم!
Your Highness!
سموك!
Your Highness
سموك
and Princess Hua
والأميرة هوا
are progressing so quickly.
تتقدم بسرعة كبيرة
It's beyond my imagination.
هذا يتجاوز خيالي
Don't simply say that.
لا تقل ذلك ببساطة
Princess Hua and I didn't do anything.
أنا والأميرة هوا لم أفعل أي شيء
I was trying to upset her
كنت أحاول إزعاجها
and she looked for a guy
وكانت تبحث عن رجل
to keep rubbing
للحفاظ على صحة
my body
جسدي
using a rough stone.
باستخدام حجر خام
I almost lost my life there.
كدت أن أفقد حياتي هناك
Princess Hua
الأميرة هوا
invited Your Highness to a rubbing bath.
دعتك إلى حمام تحت الأنقاض
A rubbing bath?
حمام أنقاض؟
What's a rubbing bath?
يا له من حمام أنقاض؟
Water is scarce
المياه شحيحة
in Qinghan Prefecture.
في مقاطعة تشينغهان
It's not easy to take a bath there.
ليس من السهل الحمام هناك
Not to mention to soak in water for a bath.
ناهيك عن التربة في الماء لحمام
It's rare and expensive.
إنها نادرة وباهظة الثمن
It's precious
إنه ثمين
in normal families.
في الأسر العادية
They'd take a stone
سيأخذون حجر
to rub their bodies.
لتدمير أجسامهم
After rubbing off the dirt,
بعد نهب الدرج
they soak themselves in the water for 20 minutes.
إنهم يزرقون في الماء لمدة 20 دقيقة
Once the hot water is poured,
حالما يُسكب الماء الساخن
the feeling...
شعور...
I feel like taking a rubbing bath.
أشعر برغبة في الحصول على حمام أنقاض
I see.
فهمت
He's the best musician in the capital!
إنه أفضل موسيقي في العاصمة!
Come and take a look!
تعالوا وألقوا نظرةً!
Listen to me, everyone!
استمعوا إليّ جميعًا!
The states are coming
تعالوا وألقوا نظرة!
and the world will be at peace.
وسيكون العالم في سلام
(Support Prince Ying) As Prince Ying of the State of Jin,
(دعم الأمير ينغ) كأمير ينغ من دولة جين
I'm taking the responsibility
أنا أتحمل مسؤولية
to present a petition for the people.
بتقديم التماس للشعب
(Support Prince Ying) So everyone,
(دعم الأمير ينغ) لذا الجميع
please support me.
أرجوك دعمني
(Support Prince Ying) I'll give the Sate of Jin a surprise.
(دعم الأمير ينغ) سأعطيكم مفاجأة
When did Jinling Garden
متى وصلت حديقة جين لينغ
start to do
بدأ في القيام بذلك
this kind of business?
هذا النوع من الأعمال؟
Your Highness,
صاحب السمو
I heard that
سمعت أنه
it's Princess Jiamin
إنها الأميرة جيامين
who spent a lot of money.
التي أنفقت الكثير من المال
Otherwise, the manager
خلاف ذلك، المدير
wouldn't have agreed so easily.
ما كانت لتوافق بسهولة
Since she wants to be a fool,
بما أنها تريد أن تكون أحمق
just let her be.
دعها وشأنها فحسب
Look.
انظر
It's crowded and lively.
انها مكتظة وحيوية
Miss,
الآنسة
why are we
لماذا نحن هنا؟
here?
هنا؟
Why are we helping Prince Ying?
لماذا نساعد الأمير ينغ؟
Helping His Highness
مساعدة سموه
and His Highness will be helping us
وسموه سيساعدنا
to deal with Hua Liuli.
للتعامل مع هوا ليولي
Support Prince Ying!
دعم الأمير ينغ!
Come and support Prince Ying!
تعالوا ودعموا الأمير ينغ!
It hurts.
هذا مؤلم
(Hua Mansion)
(طائفة هوا)
(I'm considered)
(أنا يعتبر)
(giving her enough favour.)
"تقديم خدمة كافية لها"
I'll go in myself.
سأذهب في نفسي
Yes.
نعم
(Happiness, middle)
(سعيد، وسط)
How dare someone enter Hua Mansion?
كيف يجرؤ شخص ما على دخول قصر هوا؟
Ever since
منذ ذلك الحين
His Highness came here,
جاء سموه إلى هنا
I've upgraded
لقد قمت برفع مستوى
the mechanism.
الآلية
Miss,
الآنسة
it's His Highness again!
إنه سموه مرة أخرى!
Is he here to even the score?
هل هو هنا حتى النتيجة؟
We're done!
انتهينا!
We're stopping him again!
سنوقفه مجددًا!
Turn off the mechanism quickly.
أطفئي الآلية بسرعة
Okay.
حسنًا
I'll go meet him.
سأذهب لمقابلته
(Ambitious)
(طموح)
Your Highness,
سموك
why didn't you get someone to inform us?
لماذا لم تحصل على شخص لإبلاغنا؟
Princess Hua, who are you guarding against?
الأميرة هوا من الذي تحرسه؟
The mechanism is getting more and more dangerous.
الآلية تحظى أكثر خطورة
Didn't the assassins come here?
ألم يأت القاتل إلى هنا؟
I'm just too scared.
أنا خائفة جدا
So,
لذلك
I've set another mechanism.
وضعت آلية أخرى
That's right.
هذا صحيح
A few remnants are still on the run.
بعض البقايا ما زالت هاربة
You should be careful.
يجب أن تتوخي الحذر
If I knew Your Highness is coming,
إذا كنت أعرف أن سموك قادم
how would I turn on
كيف يمكنني التعامل
the mechanism?
الآلية؟
Your Highness,
صاحبة السمو
do you want to go in and take a rest?
هل تريد الدخول للراحة؟
Let me
دعيني
sew the sleeve for you.
نظف النوم لك
Please.
أرجوك
Princess Hua, your sewing skill...
الأميرة هوا، مهارة الخياطة الخاصة بك...
Not bad, right?
ليست سيئة، أليس كذلك؟
(No way.)
(مستحيل)
It comes naturally.
إنه يأتي بشكل طبيعي
You're talented.
أنت موهوب
Thank you.
شكرا لك
Your Highness,
صاحبة السمو
why not we use white string?
لماذا لا نستخدم الخيط الأبيض؟
Is that okay?
هل هذا جيد؟
I think
أعتقد
I don't want to trouble you, Princess Hua.
لا أريد إزعاجك الأميرة هوا
No worries.
لا قلقي
It's not necessary.
هذا ليس ضروريًا
No worries. Don't...
لا تقلق، لا...
No worries.
لا قلقي
Give it to me. No worries.
أعطيه لي لا قلقي
It seems like
يبدو وكأنه
I need to sew it.
أحتاج إلى الغوص فيه
It's torn.
إنها ممزقة
The rubbing bath that day
حمام الأنقاض في ذلك اليوم
is a practice in Qinghan Prefecture?
هل هو ممارسة في مقاطعة تشينغهان؟
Yes.
نعم
I brought the stone here
أحضرت الحجر هنا
from Qinghan Prefecture.
من مقاطعة تشينغهان
Bathing using that stone
استحمام باستخدام ذلك الحجر
refreshes us.
ينشطنا
However,
لكن
it doesn't seem suitable.
لا يبدو مناسبا
Why is it not suitable?
لماذا هو غير مناسب؟
In Qinghan Prefecture,
في محافظة تشينغهان
water is so much lesser than human.
المياه أقل بكثير من الإنسان
We only have a big lake.
لدينا فقط بحيرة كبيرة
Most importantly,
الاهم
people from Jinpo
الناس من جينبو
are fighting for it with us.
يقاتلون من أجلها معنا
So, if we won,
لذلك، إذا فزنا
we'd be able to get some borders.
سنتمكن من الوصول إلى بعض الحدود
Then we'll be able to
إذن سنتمكن من
take more showers.
أخذ المزيد من الاستحمام
If we lose,
إذا خسرنا
we'll have to use water
سيتعين علينا استخدام المياه
wisely in that whole year.
في ذلك العام بأكمله
But after I came to the capital,
ولكن بعد أن جئت إلى العاصمة
I realised that
أدركت أنني
using water
استخدام المياه
isn't difficult here.
ليس صعبا هنا
So I thought
لذلك فكرت بك
I could please Your Highness.
يمكنني رؤيتك يا أمير
However...
لكن
Actually,
في الحقيقة
I think taking a bath every now and then
أعتقد أن أغتسل كل مرة
is kind of fresh.
جيد بعض الشيء
Princess, you're overly concerned.
يا أميرة، أنت قلقة أكثر من اللازم
Do you really think so?
هل تظن ذلك حقًا؟
Of course.
بالطبع
Don't move.
لا تتحركي
(Hua Liuli)
(هوا ليولي)
(looks cute)
(يبدو ظريفا)
(sometimes.)
(أحيانا)
Stay calm.
اهدأ
Almost there.
على وشك الوصول
Look.
انظر
What's this?
ما هذا؟
Well...
إذن
This big white bear
هذا الدب الأبيض الكبير
looks lively.
يبدو حيويا
This is not a big white bear.
هذا ليس دب أبيض كبير
Could it be a small white rat?
هل يمكن أن يكون فأرا أبيض صغيرا؟
No.
لا
Obviously this is Fafa.
من الواضح أن هذا هو الفافا
Is it not obvious?
أليس هذا واضحا؟
Fafa?
القوات المسلحة الاتحادية؟
So you've giving this scented sachet to me?
لذا هل أعطيتني هذا هذا الكيس المُعطّر لي؟
Didn't I make it obvious
ألم أجعل الأمر واضحا
for the last few days?
خلال الأيام القليلة الماضية؟
Obvious?
واضح؟
How is it obvious?
ما هو الواضح؟
Look.
انظر
My fingers are hurt.
أصابعي تتأذى
Look. Here.
انظري، هنا
Here, here,
هنا
here and here.
وهنا
It hurts.
هذا مؤلم
Look.
انظر
Princess Hua, you must rest well.
الأميرة هوا، يجب أن تستريحي جيدا
Here. I've roughly sewn it.
هنا، لقد غرقته تقريبا
Your Highness, are you satisfied?
صاحب السمو، هل أنت راض؟
I'm satisfied.
أنا سعيد
Your Highness,
سموك
can we
هل يمكننا
talk nicely now?
نتحدث بلطف الآن؟
Princess Hua, you wanted
الأميرة هوا، كنت تريد
to cut ties with me so badly before.
قطع العلاقات معي بشدة من قبل
Now, you're trying to be nice to me.
الآن، تحاول أن تكون لطيفا معي
With my
بشخصيتي
doubtful personality,
شخصيتي المشكوك فيها
it's hard for me
من الصعب عليّ
not to overthink.
ألا أبالغ في التفكير
However, the scented sachet
ومع ذلك، الكيس المُعطّر
is a token from you.
هو رمز منك
I'll keep it.
سأحتفظ بها
(Hua Mansion)
(حفل هوا)
Why isn't His Highness coming out yet?
لماذا لم يخرج سموه بعد؟
Your Highness.
صاحبة السمو
Your...
الأمير...
This...
هذا...
Where did you pick up the scented sachet?
من أين أجبت الكيس المُعطّر؟
It's so ugly.
إنه قبيح جدًا
I didn't pick it up.
لم أردّ
It's a gift.
إنها هدية
Did Princess Hua sew it for you?
هل تركته الأميرة هوا لك؟
She sewed it.
لقد بحثتها
Your favourite
المفضل لديك
thing in Ankang Garden.
شيء في حديقة آنكانغ
This is too cute.
هذا ظريف جدا
Look at the scented sachet.
انظري إلى الكيس المُعطّر
It matches perfectly
إنه يطابق تماما
with Your Highness.
مع سموك
It's a match in heaven.
إنها مباراة في السماء
A perfect match.
مباراة مثالية
Didn't you say it's ugly?
ألم تقولي إنه قبيح؟
I was talking about myself.
كنت أتحدث عن نفسي
Your Highness,
صاحبة السمو
how was your conversation
كيف كانت محادثتك
with Princess Hua?
مع الأميرة هوا؟
She kept me
لقد احتفظت بي
chasing after her before this.
مطاردتها قبل هذا
Now, it's her turn.
الآن، حان دورها
The matter involves Hua family.
الأمر يتعلق بعائلة هوا
She has to take action.
عليها أن تتخذ إجراء
We just need to wait.
نحن بحاجة فقط إلى الانتظار
(Didn't we come here for an inspection?)
(ألم نأتي إلى هنا للتفتيش؟)
(His Highness...)
(الأمير)
Your Highness, you're wise.
الأمير، أنت حكيم
Besides that,
إلى جانب ذلك
I have other plans
لدي خطط أخرى
for the two assassins.
لكل من القاتل
I told you that it's not simple.
أخبرتك أن الأمر ليس بسيطا
His Highness is
سموه هو
the Crown Prince.
ولي عهد
Does His Highness need to work hard?
هل يحتاج سموه إلى العمل الجاد؟
No need.
لا حاجة
If His Highness doesn't need to work hard,
إذا لم يكن سموه يحتاج إلى العمل الجاد
why does His Highness need to fight against Prince Ying?
لماذا يحتاج سموه إلى القتال ضد الأمير ينغ؟
But who else
ولكن من غيره
if not His Highness?
إذا لم يكن سموه؟
Why not we talk to
لماذا لا نتحدث
Prince Ying
الأمير ينغ
and ask His Highness to change his mind?
ويطلب من سموه تغيير رأيه؟
Think about it.
فكر في الأمر
Who is behind Prince Ying?
من هو وراء الأمير ينغ؟
His mother, Consort Xian.
أمه، القرينة شيان
His teacher, Grand Preceptor Du.
معلمته، المعلم الكبير دو
Don't you remember what
ألا تتذكر ما هو
Grand Preceptor Du's stand is?
بمحل المعلم الكبير دو؟
We're not sure.
لسنا متأكدين
Why not we support Prince Ying?
لماذا لا ندعم الأمير ينغ؟
(Support Prince Ying) His Majesty said it's a competition.
"دعم الأمير ينغ" قال جلالته إنه مباراة
After all, there's no one else to support.
في النهاية، لا يوجد أحد وأيضا للدعم
Obviously, His Majesty
من الواضح، جلالة الملك
wants His Highness to be chosen.
يريد اختيار سموه
See?
أرأيت؟
All these are about supporting Prince Ying.
كل هذا يتعلق دعم الأمير ينغ
Who are you supporting?
من أنت لدعم؟
(I must grab)
(يجب أن أمسك)
(His Highness)
(صاحب السمو)
(as my life-saving straw.)
(مثل قش إنقاذ الحياة)
It seems like
يبدو وكأنه
this weak and sick
هذا الضعيف والمرضى
beautiful princess
أميرة جميلة
has to personally
عليها أن تتخذ تدابير شخصية
beg His Highness.
اطلب من سموه
Let's go.
لنذهب
(Ankang Garden)
(حديقة آنكانغ)
Greetings, Your Highness.
تحياتي يا صاحب السمو
Is His Highness around?
هل صاحب السمو؟
I'm sorry, Your Highness.
آسف يا صاحب السمو
His Highness is not here today.
سموه ليس هنا اليوم
Did he go to the Eastern Palace?
هل ذهب إلى القصر الشرقي؟
I'm sorry, Your Highness.
أنا آسف يا صاحب السمو
I really don't know
لا أعرف حقا
where His Highness has gone to.
إلى أين ذهب سموه
Thank you.
شكرًا لك
Is His Highness
هو سموه
avoiding us?
تجنبنا؟
His Highness is pure,
سموه نقي
diligent
عليك
and smart.
وذكي
His Highness only goes to two places,
سموه يذهب إلى مكانين فقط
Ankang Garden and Eastern Palace.
حديقة أنكانغ والقصر الشرقي
If there's a case,
إذا كانت هناك قضية
Supreme Court would be another.
ستكون المحكمة العليا قضية أخرى
Tell me.
أخبرني
Where should we go
إلى أين يجب أن نذهب
to find him?
للعثور عليه؟
Why do I feel like
لماذا أشعر وكأنني
you're talking about someone else?
هل تتحدث عن شخص آخر؟
Are we not trying to please him?
ألا نحاول إرضاءه؟
We've finally caught the two assassins,
لقد قبضنا أخيرا على القاتل
but the court asked us to let them go.
ولكن المحكمة طلبت منا السماح لهما بالذهاب
Enough, Your Highness.
شكرا يا صاحب السمو
They're just some thieves.
إنهم فقط بعض اللصوص
We can let them go.
يمكننا التخلي عنهم
Your Highness, are you saying that
صاحب السمو، هل تقصد أنه
the peace negotiation
مفاوضات السلام
has to be compromised?
يجب أن يتعرض للخطر؟
Jinpo's General A'Wa
جنرال هوا
will be sent to the capital by the Hua family.
سيتم إرسالهم إلى العاصمة من قبل عائلة هوا
What are they talking about?
عمّ يتحدثون؟
Be quiet.
اصمت
However, there are
ومع ذلك، هناك
a few ignorant officers
عدد قليل من الضباط الجهلة
said that since
قال إنه منذ
Jinpo is yielding,
جينبو يستسلم
we need to show them that we're magnanimous too.
يجب أن نظيرهم أننا رائعون أيضًا
That's the officers' style
هذا هو أسلوب الضباط
in the State of Jin.
في ولاية جين
They're stupid!
إنهم غباء!
They said the peace negotiation between two states is going on.
قالوا إن مفاوضات السلام بين المقاطعتين جارية
They can't kill us anymore!
لم يعد بإمكانهم قتلنا!
So, the two thieves...
لذا فإن اللصوص
Release them.
أطلق سراحهم
Release them?
اطلق سراحهم؟
Release them!
أطلق سراحهم!
Yes.
نعم
We're...
نحن...
Free now!
مجاني الآن!
You're free.
أنت حرة
Go out.
اخرجي
If I'm not mistaken,
إذا لم أكن مخطئا
once the two thieves are released,
بمجرد إطلاق سراح اللصوص
the new assassin
القاتل الجديد
will very likely to pretend to be like them.
من المرجح جدا يتظاهر بأنه مثلهم
Even if the mastermind is not doing anything,
حتى لو كان العقل المدبر عدم القيام بأي شيء
we can find the clue and hint
يمكننا العثور على الدليل والإلهام
to catch all the assassins.
للإمساك بجميع القاتل
Your Highness, your move
صاحبة السمو، خطوتك
is amazing.
رائعة
I can even manipulate
يمكنني حتى التلاعب
Hua Liuli.
هوا ليولي
This is nothing.
لا شيء
(Supreme Court)
(المحكمة العليا)
Our old friends are here.
أصدقائنا القدامى هنا
Let's go!
لنذهب
Your Highness.
سموك
Help me take this.
ساعدني في أخذ هذا
Your Highness, I have something on.
صاحب السمو، لدي شيء ما
I'm leaving now!
سأغادر الآن!
Bai!
باي!
Yuan Wei.
يوان وي
Bai.
باي
Pei Jihuai!
بي جيهواي!
If I didn't investigate about how Miss
إذا لم أحقق عن كيف الآنسة
was poisoned in the plum blossom banquet,
تم تسميم في مأدبة زهر البرقوق
I wouldn't have known that
لم أكن أعرف
- you're His Highness' man. - I...
- أنت رجل صاحب السمو - أنا...
I...
أنا...
You're also the Junior Secretary of Supreme Court.
أنت أيضا السكرتير الأول إلى المحكمة العليا
I'm sorry.
أنا آسف
It's my fault.
إنه خطأي
Yuan Wei,
يوان وي
listen to my explanation.
استمع إلى توضيحي
can you listen to my explanation?
هل يمكنك الاستماع إلى تفسيره؟
Your Highness,
صاحبة السمو
(Supreme Court) are you going to Ankang Garden
(المحكمة العليا) هل أنت ذاهبة إلى حديقة أنكانغ
or Eastern Palace?
أو القصر الشرقي؟
It depends on my mood.
هذا يعتمد على مزاجي
Let me send you there.
دعني أرسلك إلى هناك
Or
أو
let me sit in your carriage.
دعني أجلس في عربتك
(Not again?)
(لا مرة أخرى؟)
(Can you do something new?)
(هل يمكنك القيام بشيء جديد)
I've been walking for the whole day.
لقد كنت أسير طوال اليوم
It's tiring.
إنه متعب
My legs are sore.
ساقاي تؤلمانني
Why not we do this?
لماذا لا نفعل هذا؟
Princess Hua and I
الأميرة هوا وأنا
will go to Ankang Garden.
سوف أذهب إلى حديقة أنكانغ
Okay, let's go.
حسنًا، دعنا نذهب
Yuan Wei.
يوان وي
Well,
إذن
this matter actually goes like this.
في الحقيقة، هذه المسألة
So,
لذلك
you came to work in Hua Mansion
جئت للعمل في طائفة هوا
because it's His Highness' order.
لأنه أمر سموه
Were you trying to
هل كنت تحاول
harm Hua family?
إيذاء عائلة هوا؟
That's in the past.
هذا في الماضي
It doesn't matter anymore.
لم يعد هذا مهمًا
Don't forget though.
لا تنس رغم ذلك
Princess Hua
الأميرة هوا
is asking for a favour
تطلب خدمة
from His Highness now.
من سموه الآن
You...
أنت...
You're just a liar.
أنت مجرد كاذبة
I was
كنت
feeling so sad when you were leaving.
كنت أشعر بالحزن الشديد عندما كنت تغادرين
What did you say?
ماذا قلت؟
You were what?
كنت ماذا؟
I said
قلت
you're just a liar.
أنت مجرد كاذبة
A liar!
كذاب!
Since you're saying that,
بما أنك تقولين ذلك
it was you
كنت أنت
who asked me
من طلب مني
to work for you.
أن أعمل من أجلك
I didn't think much.
لم أفكر كثيرا
Say that again!
كرر ما قلته!
Your miss
آنسة
is being harassed by His Highness!
يتعرض للمضايقة من قبل سموه!
Pei Jihuai!
بي جيهواي!
(She's trying to be nice.)
(هي تحاول أن تكون لطيفة)
(I'm afraid this is not good.)
(أخشى أن هذا ليس جيدا)
Your Highness.
صاحب السمو
I think
أعتقد
Your Highness has taken away
سموك قد أخذ
my scented sachet.
الكيس المُعطّر لي
It means
إنه يعني
you and I
أنا وأنت
have reconciled.
لقد تصالحنا
Now,
الآن
we can sit down
يمكننا الجلوس
and discuss about something.
لمناقشة شيء ما
(I knew this is coming.)
(كنت أعرف أن هذا قادم)
Fine.
حسنا
Princess Hua, you're right.
الأميرة هوا، أنت على حق
Why not you tell me straight?
لماذا لا تخبريني بشكل مستقيم؟
What's your thought?
ما رأيك؟
I'd like Your Highness
أود أن تكون سموك
to compete for the Ceremonial Officer position.
للتنافس على موظف مراسم
The Ceremonial Officer?
مسؤول المراسم؟
Princess Hua, why are you saying that?
الأميرة هوا، لماذا تقول ذلك؟
For the sake of Hua family.
عائلة هوا
Your Highness knows that
سموك يعرف أن
only Prince Ying alone
فقط الأمير ينغ وحده
is competing for the Ceremonial Officer position.
يتنافس على منصب موظف الاحتفال
But His Highness
لكن صاحب السمو
isn't friendly
ليس وديا
towards Hua family.
نحو عائلة هوا
I think
أعتقد
Hua family shouldn't be treated this way.
لا ينبغي أن تكون عائلة هوا تعامل بهذه الطريقة
What does it
ما علاقتي
have to do with me?
له علاقة بي؟
I think
أعتقد
Your Highness will become the future Emperor.
سموك ستصبح الإمبراطور المستقبلي
You'll consider the peace
ستعتبر السلام
between the two states.
بين المقاطعتين
Even if Your Highness' idea
حتى لو كانت فكرة سموك
is different
مختلفة
from His Highness,
من سموه
but only when two swords meet,
ولكن فقط عندما تجتمع سيفتان
we'll know which one is sharper.
سنعرف أي واحد هو أكثر حدة
I'm just trying to fight for
أنا فقط أحاول القتال من أجل
Hua family's reputation.
سمعة عائلة هوا
The future Emperor?
الإمبراطور المستقبلي؟
Don't you know
لا تعرف
how others
كيف الآخرين
are criticising me?
التي تنتقدني؟
I know,
أعرف
but I think
لكنني أعتقد
it's because Your Highness doesn't know how to express
لأن سموك لا يعرف كيفية التعبير
or you don't think there's a need to express at all.
أم لا تعتقد أن هناك حاجة للتعبير على الإطلاق
That's why the misunderstanding was created.
لهذا السبب تم خلق سوء الفهم
Your Highness gave Hua Mansion to me
أعطى سموك لي طائفة هوا
and you guarded it
وأنت حراسته
to protect me.
لحميني
Your Highness, you've
صاحب السمو، لقد أنقذتني
saved me many times.
أنقذتني عدة مرات
So I think...
لذلك أعتقد
Fruit jam was made into blood.
جعل شمس الفاكهة دم
Food supply was cut and you used it to earn money.
تم قطع الإمدادات الغذائية واستخدمته لكسب المال
A shabby mansion was made luxury.
قصر المهر كان ترفا
The assassins failed all the time.
فشل القاتل طوال الوقت
You've done so many things
لقد فعلت الكثير من الأشياء
one after another.
واحدا تلو الآخر
Princess Hua, you're so smart.
الأميرة هوا، أنت ذكية جدًا
Why do you need my favour?
لماذا تحتاج إلى صالحي؟
Your Highness, are you blaming me?
صاحب السمو، هل تلومني؟
I'm complimenting you.
أنا أثني عليك
Hold on.
تمسكي
Actually, I've been meaning to say
في الحقيقة، كنت أريد أن أقول
you don't have to
ليس عليك
pretend in front of me.
تظاهر أمامي
You can actually...
في الحقيقة...
So Your Highness has never
لذلك الأمير لم تثق بي
trusted me
وثقت بي
and has been doubting Hua family's
وما برح يشكك في
loyalty to the imperial court.
بالولاء إلى العودة
I believe
أعتقد
Your Highness and I
أنا وصاحب السمو
have nothing to talk about.
ليس لدي ما أتحدث عنه
I'm leaving.
سأغادر
Princess!
الأميرة!
Look at what I've done.
انظري إلى ما فعلته
(Elegance)
(المؤمنين)
Greetings, Your Highness.
تحياتي يا صاحب السمو
Your Highness, the tea is here.
صاحبة السمو، الشاي هنا
Princess,
الملكة
weren't you upset?
ألم تكوني منزعجة؟
Your Highness, you know
أمير، أنت تعلم
that I don't do things for nothing.
أنني لا شيء
I've done so many thing for Your Highness lately.
لقد فعلت الكثير من الشيء لسموك في الآونة الأخيرة
I need to drink the tea before I leave.
أحتاج إلى شرب الشاي قبل أن أغادر
Come
هيا
and serve Princess tea.
وتقديم شاي الأميرة
Yes.
نعم
Your Highness.
سموك
How could you treat the servant this way?
كيف يمكنك معاملة الخادم بهذا الطريقة؟
Look at her hands.
انظري إلى يديها
Her fingers are so rough.
أصابعها خشنة جدًا
Even her Hoku
حتى هوكو
is rough.
شكرا
It's similar
إنه مشابه
to the guy I know
على الرجل الذي أعرفه
who is always holding a sword.
الذي يملك دائما سيف
Guard!
احترسي!
Miss,
الآنسة
His Highness is a nice guy.
سموه رجل لطيف
Why are you doing this?
لماذا تفعل هذا؟
Your Highness, are you okay?
صاحب السمو، هل أنت بخير؟
I've been serving in Ankang Garden for a few years
لقد كنت أخدم في حديقة أنكانغ لبضع سنوات
for today.
لهذا اليوم
You've ruined my plan
لقد أفسدت خطتي
and you're pretending to be innocent.
وأنت تتظاهر بالبراءة
I really didn't mean it.
أنا حقًا لم أقصد ذلك
You...
أنت...
You've been waiting by my side for a few years.
كنت تنتظر بجانبي لبضع سنوات
Not bad.
لست سيئة
You're taking the opportunity
أنت تنتهز الفرصة
to frame the two Jinpo assassins
لتأطير قاتل جينبو
as soon as I've released them.
بمجرد أن أفرج عنهم
Do you know
هل تعرف
this was my plan?
كانت هذه خطتي؟
Take her to the Supreme Court.
خذها إلى المحكمة العليا
Interrogate her and find out who her mastermind is.
وقم باستجوابها لمعرفة من هو العقل المدبر لها
- Yes.
- نعم
Also,
وأيضا
investigate everyone in the chamber
تحقيق في الجميع في الغرفة
and Eastern Palace again.
والقصر الشرقي مرة أخرى
Take her away.
خذها بعيدا
- Yes.
- نعم
Princess, are you frightened?
يا برينسيس، هل تخيفة؟
This is too frightening.
هذا مخيف جدًا
Greetings, Your Highness.
تحياتي يا صاحب السمو
(This servant)
(هذا الخادم)
(walks without making any sound.)
(يهين دون صنع أي صوت)
I'm so sorry.
أنا آسف جدًا
I've hit you accidentally.
لقد ضربتك عرضا
Be careful, Your Highness.
كن حذرا يا صاحب السمو
(She knows martial arts.)
(إنها تعرف فنون الدفاع عن النفس)
(This is bad.)
(هذا سيء)
I should
يجب علي
thank you for just now, Princess Hua.
شكرا لك على الفور، الأميرة هوا
Ceremonial Officer, right?
موظفة مراسم، أليس كذلك؟
Fine.
حسنا
I promise you.
أعدك
Come to the Hall of Great Awakening tomorrow
تعالي إلى قاعة الصحوة الكبرى غدا
and wait for my good news.
وأنتظر أخباري الجيدة
(Hua Mansion)
(حفل هوا)
(Ambitious)
(طموح)
Let me eat this too.
دعيني آكل هذا أيضًا
I was really frightened just now.
كنت خائفة حقًا قبل قليل
I need to eat more
يجب أن آكل أكثر
to replenish myself.
لتجديد موارد نفسي
Are you listening to yourself?
هل تسمعين إلى نفسك؟
You almost exposed your martial arts today.
كدت تكشف فنون الدفاع عن النفس الخاصة بك اليوم
Have you forgotten
هل نسيت
what you promised General Hua?
ما وعدته الجنرال هوا؟
What do you know?
لا تعرف شيئا
I did that
لقد فعلت ذلك
to please His Highness
لإرضاء سموه
so that His Highness would compete with Prince Ying.
بحيث سموه سوف ينافس مع الأمير ينغ
Was it easy for me to do all those?
هل كان من السهل عليّ فعل كل ذلك؟
Miss,
الآنسة
look at my eyes.
انظرا إلى عينيّ
What's wrong with your eyes?
ما خطب عينيك؟
You didn't wash your face today.
لم تغسل وجهك اليوم
Miss!
الآنسة!
All right.
حسنًا
I'll stop.
سأتوقف
Let me see.
دعني أرى
Your big eyes are red and swollen.
عيناك الكبيرتان حمراء ومتأنقتان
Did you cry again
هل كنت تبكي مرة أخرى
for Pei Jihuai today?
بي جيهواي اليوم؟
How did you know?
كيف عرفت؟
He's terrible.
إنه فظيع
He cheated me for my feeling.
خدع بي على شعوري
He ran away when he saw me.
هرب عندما رآني
That's too much.
هذا مبالغ فيه
When I see him next time,
عندما أراه في المرة القادمة
I'll teach him a lesson for you.
سألقنه درسًا لك
Miss, you're taking it too far off.
الآنسة، أنت تأخذينها بعيدًا جدًا
Look at my eyes.
انظري إلى عينيّ
All right.
حسنًا
Miss,
الآنسة
tell me honestly and sincerely.
و
Are you attracted by his look
هل جذبتك مظهره
and you're in love with His Highness?
وأنت في حب الأمير؟
I'm just pitying him
أنا أشفق عليه فقط
because he's just like me.
لأنه مثلي تمامًا
Someone wants to kill him.
شخص ما يريد قتله
Someone wants to kill me.
شخص ما يريد قتلي
Who else would help him if I'm not helping him?
من سيساعده غيري إذا لم أساعده؟
You're too nosy.
أنت فضولية جدًا
Get the snacks here.
أرسلي الوجبات الخفيفة إلى هنا
Hurry.
هيا
You're talkative.
أنت ثرثارة
(She's so smart.)
(إنها ذكية جدا)
(Luckily I responded quickly.)
(لحسن الحظ استجابت بسرعة)
(Ankang Garden)
(حديقة آنكانغ)
(Grace)
(غريس)
Let's go!
لنذهب
Your Highness,
صاحب السمو
I'll interrogate
سأقوم بالاستجواب
these few people.
هؤلاء الناس القلائل
But for safety purpose,
ولكن لغرض السلامة
should we change
إذا غيرنا
all the people
جميع الناس
in Ankang Garden?
في حديقة أنكانغ؟
Including Eastern Palace.
بما في ذلك القصر الشرقي
Yes.
نعم
Young Master,
سيد
all the people that
جميع الناس الذين
we've sent to His Highness' side
لقد أرسلنا إلى جانب سموه
has been changed.
تم تغييره
I wonder how
أتساءل كيف
we'll deal with this.
كيفية تعاملنا مع هذا
We shouldn't take any action now.
لا ينبغي لنا أن نتخذ أي إجراء الآن
We need to wait for another opportunity.
نحن بحاجة إلى الانتظار فرصة أخرى
Or
أو
you wish to see
هل تريد أن ترى
me being involved?
أنا متورطة؟
No.
لا
Master
معلمي
doesn't want us to
لا يريدنا
to dwell here for fun
العيش هنا للتسلية
and forget about our assignment.
ونسي مهمتنا
(Yunzhong Hall) Your Highness, you're here.
(قاعة يونزهونغ) الملكة، أنت هنا
Miss.
الآنسة
Didn't you want to
ألم ترغب في
practise walking like a feeble beauty?
ممارسة المشي مثل جمال ضعيف؟
Why are you writing now?
لماذا تكتب الآن؟
I'm not writing.
أنا لا أكتب
Well, Prince Ying
حسنًا، الأمير ينغ
and His Highness are competing.
وصاحب السمو يتنافسان
I want to help him
أريد أن أساعده
so I've concluded something.
لذلك أبرمت شيئا
Look.
انظر
Prince Ying's strength.
قوة الأمير ينغ
Diligent, easygoing
دؤوبة، متجهة نحو الشرق
and polite.
والمهذبة
Shortcomings.
عيوب
Arrogant, stupid
غرور وغبي
and ordinary.
و
(Arrogant, stupid)
(متعجرف وغبي)
Crown Prince's strength.
قوة ولي عهد
None.
لا يوجد
There's indeed none.
لا يوجد أي منها بالفعل
Crown Prince's shortcomings.
عيوب ولي عهد
Notorious, cruel, unpredictable,
سيئة السمعة، قاسية، لا يمكن التنبؤ بها
eccentric, bully,
غريبة الأطوار
stir up trouble for no reason, neglect one's work,
لا داعي لإثارة المشاكل وإهمال عمل المرء
indulgent in seeking pleasure, insensitive to others' feelings,
مثابر على السعي إلى المتعة غير حساس بمشاعر الآخرين
and cruel.
قاس جدًا
Well...
إذن
His Highness's reputation
سمعة سموه
is so bad.
سيئة جدا
From infamy to fame
من العار إلى الشهرة
is very difficult.
صعب جدا
Your Highness.
سموك
I want to withdraw
أريد أن أسحب
my prejudice towards Hua family.
تحيز ضد عائلة هوا
Is it because Princess Hua managed
هل لأن الأميرة هوا تمكنت من
to find the assassin?
للعثور على القاتل؟
Not just that.
ليس ذلك فقط
Even though Princess Hua
على الرغم من أن الأميرة هوا
is suspicious,
مشبوهة
schemeful
منشقة
and pretentious,
وتظاهر بأنه
there's one thing
هناك شيء واحد
that she can't pretend.
لا يمكنها التظاهر به
Although we've killed 10,000 enemies
على الرغم من أننا قتلت 10،000 عدو
in the war,
في الحرب
Jin Army was only left with few thousands.
جيش جين لم يتبق سوى بضع آلاف
None of them was living for themselves.
لم يكن أي منهم يعيش من أجل نفسه
None of them died for themselves.
لم يموت أي منهم من أجل أنفسهم
They fought for their parents.
قاتلا من أجل والديهما
They fought for their children.
حاربوا من أجل أبنائهم
They fought for
قاتلا من أجل
the peace in the State of Jin.
السلام في دولة جين
When Hua family was being suspected,
عندما كان يشتبه في عائلة هوا
she felt the pain
شعرت بالألم
and the patriotism hidden
والوطنية مخفية
in her bones
في عظامها
can't be pretended.
لا يمكن التظاهر
Your Highness...
سموك
I want to try to trust her.
أريد أن أحاول الوثوق بها
Just like how I trust you.
تماما مثل مدى ثقتي بك
I've spoken to you all a few days back
لقد تكلمت إليكم جميعا قبل بضعة أيام
regarding choosing
فيما يتعلق باختيار
a Ceremonial Officer
موظف مراسم
to host the States Assembly.
لاستضافة جمعية الدول
Besides Yuanhao,
إلى جانب يوانهاو
is there anyone else
هل هناك أي شخص آخر
who is willing to try?
من على استعداد للمحاولة؟
If there's none,
إذا لم يكن هناك أحد
this matter
هذه المسألة
Father.
أبي
will...
سوف
I have an idea.
لدي فكرة
What?
ماذا؟
Are you joining the competition?
هل ستنضمين إلى المسابقة؟
I'm not suitable,
أنا لست مناسبًا
but I
لكنني
have a suitable candidate.
لدي مرشح مناسب
Who is it?
من هو؟
Protector General Hua's daughter,
ابنة المحمي الجنرال هوا
Princess Hua Liuli.
الأميرة هوا ليولي
What?
ماذا؟
Hua Liuli?
هوا ليولي؟
How can I be competing with Princess Hua
كيف يمكنني أن أتنافس مع الأميرة هوا
for the position?
للوظيفة؟
No way.
لا يمكن
Crown Prince's suggestion
اقتراح ولي عهد
is impactful.
له تأثير
Why do you say so?
لماذا تقول ذلك؟
All the states that are coming
جميع المقاطعات التي قادمة
have been defeated by the Hua family before,
هزمت عائلة هوا من قبل
especially Jinpo.
خاصة جينبو
All the shame of being defeated
كل عار من الهزيمة
was given by the Hua family.
أعطاه عائلة هوا
His Highness
سموه
is suggesting Hua Liuli
يوحي هوا ليولي
so that he'll gather the flaws of the Hua family.
حتى يستطيع جمع العيوب من عائلة هوا
Ridiculous.
سخيفة
How can you do that?
كيف يمكنك فعل ذلك؟
That's the States Assembly.
هذه هي جمعية الولايات
How can we let Miss Hua
كيف يمكن أن ندع الآنسة هوا
become the host?
أن يصبح المضيف؟
Your Majesty,
صاحب الجلالة
you mustn't agree to that.
يجب ألا توافق على ذلك
Well,
إذن
summon Hua Liuli to the court tomorrow.
استدع هوا ليولي إلى المحكمة غدا
Father,
أبي
Princess Hua happens to be at outside.
الأميرة هوا تكون في الخارج
What's going on?
ماذا يجري؟
San Cai, bring Hua Liuli in.
سان كاي، أحضري هوا ليولي إلى هناك
Yes.
نعم
Ways to save His Highness' reputation.
سبل حفظ سمعة سموه
What do you think?
ما رأيك
This is funny.
هذا مضحك
Why is my eye
لماذا عيني
twitching so badly today?
ترتعش بشدة اليوم؟
Left eye or right eye?
العين الأيسر أو العين الصحيحة؟
Left eye.
العين الأيسر
Left eye twitching is good.
تمطر العين الأيسر جيد
You said the same thing the other day.
قلت الشيء نفسه في ذلك اليوم
I was found out by mother
اكتشفت أمي أمري
for reading storybook
لقراءة القصص
and I had to copy the books for a month.
و اضطرت إلى نسخ الكتب لمدة شهر
That's because the book you read
هذا لأن الكتاب الذي قرأته
was
كان
"Domineering General's Love
"حب الجنرال المهيمن"
For Beauty"
من أجل الجميلة "
Princess Hua.
الأميرة هوا
(Chenming Palace)
(قصر تشينغ)
Eunuch Zhao.
الخصي تشاو
You're really here.
أنت هنا حقا
His Majesty is summoning you to the palace.
جلالة الإمبراطور يدعو إليك إلى القصر
Summoning me?
استدعاني؟
Please come with me.
تعال معي من فضلك
(Pretentious Hour)
(لحظة التظاهر)
(Support Prince Ying)
(دعم الأمير ينغ)
Here you go.
ها أنت ذي
Who am I?
من أنا؟
What am I doing?
ماذا أفعل؟
Why should I support Prince Ying?
لماذا يجب أن أدعم الأمير ينغ؟
Who are you supporting if it's not His Highness?
من أنت لدعم إذا لم يكن سموه؟
Are you not supporting me?
ألا تدعمني؟
Support me and you need to support His Highness.
دعم لي وأنت بحاجة لدعم سموه
Supporting His Highness means you're supporting me.
دعماً لسموه يعني أنك تدعمني
Of course I support you.
بالطبع أدعمك
All right.
حسنًا
♪A new song is played by my fingers♪
♪ أغنية جديدة يعزف بها أصابعي ♪
♪I can't talk or sleep under the moon♪
♪ لا أستطيع التحدث أو النوم تحت القمر ♪
♪I'm missing someone walking around the pavilion♪
♪ أفتقد شخصا ما أتجول حول الجناح ♪
♪I can hardly tell anyone♪
♪ لا أستطيع أن أقول لأي شخص ♪
♪Who will be in this mortal♪
♪ من سيكون في هذه الوفاة ♪
♪Know my heart and how I cry without showing anyone♪
♪ عرفت قلبي وأنت كيف أبكي دون إظهار أي شخص ♪
♪The memory has gone♪
♪ لقد اختفت الذاكرة ♪
♪Whose face is showing in my dream♪
♪ يظهر وجهي في حلمي ♪
♪How many times do I need to go through this♪
♪ كم مرة أحتاج إلى المرور بهذا ♪
♪Crying alone in front of the window♪
♪ الزواج وحده أمام النافذة ♪
♪Hearing the rain last night♪
♪ الاستماع إلى المطر ليلة أمس ♪
♪But my heart will not change♪
♪ لكن قلبي لن يتغير ♪
♪The clouds are being covered by the shadow of the moon♪
♪ الغيوم يتم تغطيتها في ظل القمر ♪
♪Who is rolling up the sleeve with the wind♪
♪ من يدمر النوم بالرياح ♪
♪Not worried about the grudges but for the ones not around♪
♪ لا تقلق بشأن الضغينة ولكن من لا حولها ♪
♪Telling my sorrowfulness in Fengyi Pavilion♪
♪ عزيمة في جناح فنغ يي ♪
♪But it's a shame a few autumns have passed♪
♪ لكنه من المؤسف لقد مرت بعض الأوهام ♪
♪It's hard to balance between the world and the one we love♪
♪ من الصعب التوازن بين العالم بين العالم الذي نحب ♪
♪The clouds are being covered by the shadow of the moon♪
♪ الغيوم يتم تغطيتها في ظل القمر ♪
♪I'm waiting while turning back♪
♪ أنا أنتظر بينما أعود ♪
♪I sighed as the old days are no longer here anymore♪
♪ شاهدت كالأيام الخوالي لم يعد هنا بعد الآن ♪
♪How many worries are there♪
♪ كم عدد الهموم هناك ♪
♪How many of us can grow old together♪
♪ كم الكثير منا يمكن أن يكبر في السن معا ♪
♪I wish you can have the world and the one you love♪
♪ أتمنى أن يكون لديك العالم العالم الذي تحبينه ♪